Register of the State Historical Society of Wisconsin Collection, circa 1900-1919
Hoover Institution Archives
State Historical Society of Wisconsin Collection,
circa 1900-1919
69024
State Historical Society of Wisconsin
2 manuscript boxes, 2 boxes of glass plates (1.9 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Depicts military camps in the United States during World War I, miscellaneous World War I scenes in Europe, and scenes from the Boxer Rebellion in China. Includes glass plate negatives. Collected by the State Historical Society of Wisconsin.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research. Glass plates may be viewed only under supervision of archivist. 35mm access slides of some glass plates are available; these are noted in finding aid.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1969.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Depicts military camps in the United States during World War I, miscellaneous World War I scenes in Europe, and scenes from the Boxer Rebellion in China. Includes prints, negatives, postcards, and glass plate negatives. Collected by the State Historical Society of Wisconsin, the original organization, titles, and numbering have been retained.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into three series: Military camps negatives, prints and postcards, World War I miscellaneous prints, and World War I and Boxer Rebellion glass plate negatives.
Access Points
United States. Army--Pictorial works.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Pictorial works.; China.; China--History--Boxer Rebellion, 1899-1901--Pictorial works.; United States--Armed Forces.; State Historical Society of Wisconsin.
Container List
- Military camps negatives, prints and postcards, 1917-1918. (Folder 1-2)
  Contains images relating to United States military camps of the period 1917-1918. It is arranged by camp name or location.
  - Fort Bliss, El Paso, Texas (20 negatives, 33 prints) (Folder 1: 1)
  - Camp Bowie, Fort Worth, Texas (1 negative) (Folder 1: 2)
  - Fort Casey, Washington (6 negatives) (Folder 1: 3)
  - Charleston, South Carolina, U.S Naval training camp (70 negatives) (Folder 1: 4)
  - Fort Devens, Ayer, Massachusetts (148 negatives) (Folder 1: 5)
  - Fort Dix, Wrightstown, New Jersey (48 negatives, 30 prints, 2 postcards) (Folder 1: 6)
  - Camp Doniphan and Fort Sill, Oaklahoma (33 negatives) (Folder 1: 7)
  - Camp Fremont, California (42 negatives) (Folder 1: 8)
  - Camp Funston, Kansas (25 negatives) (Folder 1: 9)
  - Camp Grant, Rickford, Illinois (2 negatives) (Folder 1: 10)
  - Hampton Roads, Virginia, Naval Operating Base; Naval Aviators (80 negatives, 1 print) (Folder 1: 11)
  - Camp Hancock, Augusta, Georgia (41 negatives) (Folder 1: 12)
  - Camp Harry Jones, Douglas, Arizona (29 negatives, 1 print) (Folder 1: 13)
  - Camp Humphreys, Virginia (84 negatives, 1 print) (Folder 1: 14)
  - Camp Johnston, Jacksonville, FL (22 postcards) (Folder 1: 15)
  - Camp Kearney, California (64 negatives) (Folder 1: 16)
  - Laredo, Texas (4 negatives, 1 print) (Folder 1: 17)
  - Camp Lee, Petersburg, Virginia (13 negatives, 13 prints) (Folder 1: 18)
  - Camp Lewis, Washington (81 negatives, 4 prints) (Folder 1: 19)
  - Camp Logan, Houston, Texas (2 negatives) (Folder 1: 20)
  - Camp Lynch, Washington, DC, American University camp (17 negatives, 16 prints) (Folder 1: 21)
  - Fort Myer, Virginia, Washington, DC) (24 negatives, 11 prints) (Folder 1: 22)
  - Newport News, Virginia (6 negatives) (Folder 2: 1)
  - Parris Island, South Carolina (198 negatives, 4 prints) (Folder 2: 2)
  - Camp Pike, Little Rock, AR (46 negatives) (Folder 2: 3)
  - Portsmouth, Virginia battleships (2 negatives) (Folder 2: 4)
  - Quantico, Virginia (U.S. Marine) (41 negatives, 28 prints) (Folder 2: 5)
  - U.S. Hospital Ship Repose, 1946 (16 negatives) (Folder 2: 6)
  - Camp Roberts, California (1 negative) (Folder 2: 7)
  - Saint Helena, Norfolk, Virginia (Naval Training Station) (39 negatives, 6 prints) (Folder 2: 8)
  - Camp Shelby, Mississippi (44 negatives) (Folder 2: 9)
  - Fort Sill, Oaklahoma (9 negatives) (Folder 2: 10)
  - Camp Travis, San Antonio, Texas, 1918 (3 negatives) (Folder 2: 11)
  - Camp Vail, New Jersey (3 negatives) (Folder 2: 12)
  - Washington, D.C. Marine barracks (36 negatives) (Folder 2: 13)
- Miscellaneous prints World War I, circa 1900-1919 (Folder 2)
  - World War I in France (3 prints) (Folder 2: 14)
  - One little map of Hungary (Folder 2: 15)
  - Pamphlet, Young Women's Christian Association Overseas, 1919 (Folder 2: 16)
  - Panoramic portraits, World War I (2 prints) (Folder 2: 17)
- World War I and Boxer Rebellion glass negatives, circa 1900-1919. (Folder 3-4)
  Contains images related to Allied Europe, Belgium, the Boxer Rebellion, and Canada. Arranged alphabetically by subject. Glass plates may be viewed only under supervision of archivist.
  - Allied Europe (42 glass negatives) (Folder 3)
    - 2461 - 2463 (Folder 3)
    - 2465 (Folder 3)
    - 2477 - 2479 (Folder 3)
    - 2481 (Folder 3)
    - 2485 - 2489 (Folder 3)
    - 2494 - 2496 (Folder 3)
    - 2498 - 2512 (Folder 3)
    - 2514 - 2518 (Folder 3)
    - 2520 (Folder 3)
    - 2523 - 2525 (Folder 3)
    - 2529 (Folder 3)
    - 2532 (Folder 3)
  - "Belgium's Pathetic Story" (18 glass negatives) (Folder 3)
    - 3393 (Folder 3)
    - 3464 (Folder 3)
    - 3470 (Folder 3)
    - 3486 (Folder 3)
    - 3498 - 3499 (Folder 3)
    - 3503 - 3504 (Folder 3)
    - 3509 (Folder 3)
    - 3512 - 3514 (Folder 3)
    - 3516 (Folder 3)
    - 3520 (Folder 3)
    - 3529 (Folder 3)
    - 3534 - 3536 (Folder 3)
  - Boxer Rebellion (35 glass negatives), 1898-1901 (Folder 3)
    - 14070 - Chinese "Boxer", (copy slide available) (Folder 3)
    - 14071 - Inside a Chinese arsenal, Tientsin (Tainjin), China (Folder 3)
    - 14072 - British Indian troops in camp, Peking (Beijing), China (Folder 3)
    - 14073 - Fortifications, Taku, China, (copy slide available) (Folder 3)
    - 14074 - The Great Wall of China, near Shang-Hai-Kwan, 1901 (Folder 3)
    - 14075 - The Summer Palace, near Peking (Beijing), 1900; (copy slide available) (Folder 3)
    - 14076 - Russian troops returning from march into the Forbidden City, Peking (Beijing), China, (copy slide available) (Folder 3)
    - 14081 - Group of distinguished Chinese officials calling on General Chaff at his headquarters in the Temple of Agriculture, Peking (Beijing), China (Folder 3)
    - 14083 - British Marines, Tientsin (Tainjin), China (Folder 3)
    - 14084 - U.S. Army officers with Japanese and American soldiers, Taku, China (Folder 3)
    - 14085 - Japanese troops returning from their march through the Forbidden City, Peking (Beijing), China, (copy slide available) (Folder 3)
    - 14086 - Near the U.S. Legation, looking N.W. from Ft. Myer on the Tartar Wall, Peking (Beijing), 1900 (Folder 3)
    - 14087 - Pagoda on wall about Peking (Beijing), China (Folder 3)
    - 14088 - Russian troops (Folder 3)
    - 14089 - American artillery during the march on Peking (Beijing), 1900 August; (copy slide available) (Folder 3)
    - 14303 - Company of American soldiers (Folder 3)
    - 14304 - Russian troops entering Peking (Beijing), China, 1900 August (Folder 3)
    - 14305 - Fort No. 2, Shang-Hai-Kwan, in March 1901, from south corner (point "C" on sketch 1901) (Folder 3)
    - 14312 - 12th Royal Field Artillery (British) with Chinese Relief Expedition, Peking (Beijing), 1900 (Folder 3)
    - 14316 - Japanese troops (Folder 3)
    - 14317 - Scene in front of Temple of Agriculture, Peking (Beijing), Camel train bringing in coal, 1900 (Folder 3)
    - 14576 - Japanese pack train en route to Peking (Beijing), China (Folder 3)
    - 14580 - Fortifications, Taku, 1900; (copy slide available) (Folder 3)
    - 14581 - View of fortifications and harbor, Taku, 1900; (copy slide available) (Folder 3)
    - 14582 - Japanese artillery, Peking (Beijing), 1900 (Folder 3)
    - 14583 - British and native officers-16th Bengal Lancers, 1900 (Folder 3)
    - 14584 - Fort No. 1, Shang-Hai-Kwan, 1900; (copy slide available) (Folder 3)
    - 14585 - Japanese pack train (Folder 3)
    - 14586 - Peking (Beijing), China, (copy slide available) (Folder 3)
    - 14587 - American troops scaling walls of gate to Peking (Beijing), China, (copy slide available) (Folder 3)
    - 14588 - Japanese troops (Folder 3)
    - 14589 - Fortifications, Taku, China, (copy slide available) (Folder 3)
    - 14590 - Artillery in action, (copy slide available) (Folder 3)
    - 14595 - Temple near Ching-Hing, on road from Peking (Beijing) to Nan-Kow pass, 1901 (Folder 3)
    - 14601 - Tower in Black Fort, Tientsin (Tainjin), 1901; (copy slide available) (Folder 3)
    - Canada (5 glass negatives) (Folder 3)
    - 22333 - French refugees returning to the re-conquered land, 1917 (Folder 3)
      (from Great War painting hanging in Senate Chamber at Ottawa)
    - 22340 - Canadian Veterinary Unit in France, 1915 (Folder 3)
    - 22889 - Landing of the 1st Canadians at St. Nazaire, France, 1915 (Folder 3)
    - 22890 - Canadian Railway Construction Corps in France, 1915 (Folder 3)
    - 22891 - Canada's "Watch on the Rhine" (Folder 3)
  - Glimpses of the Great War (83 glass negatives, 1 glass positive) (Folder 4)
    - 5589 - 5597 (Folder 4)
    - 5598, (copy slide available) (Folder 4)
    - 5599 - 5607 (Folder 4)
    - 5609 - 5633 (Folder 4)
    - 5635 - 5640 (Folder 4)
    - 5641 - Italian King with troops (Folder 4)
    - 5642 - Italian armored motorcar (Folder 4)
    - 5645 - 5652 (Folder 4)
    - 5655 - 5660 (Folder 4)
    - 5663 - 5668 (Folder 4)
    - 5671 - 5672 (Folder 4)
    - 5677 - 5683 (Folder 4)
    - 5686 - 5687 (copy slides available) (Folder 4)
    - 5688 - 5713 (Folder 4)
    - 5714, (copy slide available) (Folder 4)
    - 5715 - 5724 (Folder 4)
    - from Allied Europe (1 glass negative) (Folder 4)
    - 2578 - 2579 (Folder 4)